<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TidyTuesday on Sarah Codes</title>
    <link>https://sapo83.github.io/categories/tidytuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TidyTuesday on Sarah Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sapo83.github.io/categories/tidytuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Modern Day Comparison of 3 Heat Map Packages - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparision_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparision_part3/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 3 in my series comparing different heat map packages. You can find Part 1 here &amp;amp; Part 2 here.
In this part, I’m going to look at ComplexHeatmap. I think I first came across ComplexHeatmap on Twitter. It looks to have some really great features. The clustering &amp;amp; annotation features alone look amazing!!! This seemed like the perfect excuse to play with it a bit.
We’re going to use the same data as before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modern Day Comparison of 3 Heat Map Packages - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparison_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparison_part2/</guid>
      <description>We’re back to look at another heat map package! This is Part 2 of a 3 part series. You can find Part 1 here.
As someone who learned R using primarily the tidyverse, pheatmap had a bit of a learning curve. As a grad student, I was looking for an easier way to make a heat map with clustered data. I was trying to make heat maps for about 50 clusters in a programmatic way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modern Day Comparison of 3 Heat Map Packages - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparison_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sapo83.github.io/posts/heatmap_comparison_part1/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to use some early data from the first week of #TidyTuesday to do a comparison of different methods for making a heat map. The three packages I’m going to compare are ggplot2, pheatmap, &amp;amp; ComplexHeatmap.
The first package I’m going to look at is ggplot2, an integral part of the tidyverse.* You can create a heat map in ggplot2 using geom_tile(). One of the pros of making any type of plot in ggplot2 is it plays well with other types of plots made in ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
